If you could put anything on a
billboard, metaphorically speaking, for
millions, billions of people to see,
could be anything, image, quote,
question,
preferably not commercial.
What would it be? What might it be?
>> So, a billboard, which lots of people
are going to see, I would put, prepare
your mind. M this is a saying which is
originally Louis Pastor I think the
scientist
who said chance favors the prepared
mind. If you're ready for things you can
make the most of the opportunity that
comes your way. And the amazing thing
about this saying is that it's come up
randomly in different contexts in
different books I've done. So when I was
writing about venture capital, Excel
Capital
>> and one of the founders, Arthur
Patterson, used this phrase as a
description of how he wanted Excel to
invest that they would run these kind of
scenario exercises where they would
think, okay, there's a new technology
coming down the pike. What kind of
company needs to be built to make the
most of that new platform? What type of
entrepreneur is going to fit this
opportunity? what should we be expecting
so that the person walks into the office
into the conference room and pitches to
us we already know 90% of what he says
because we've prepared our minds and
that way we can make a good judgment and
a fast judgment if it's a competitive
situation so I kind of wrote about the
prepared mind in the context of venture
capital and then I'm doing the infinity
machine and I'm interviewing Ilia Satska
from open AI and I'm asking him why was
it you who understood the significance
of the transformer architecture
when it came out immediately like on the
day it was up on the website you read it
you ran down the corridor you went to
see your collaborator Alec Radford and
you said we're going to build a language
model on top of this architecture
>> well not only that he said stop
everything you're doing
>> right right
>> and do this
>> yeah this vision of the kind of you know
overcaffeinated charismatic
seizing on the engineer and saying drop
it whatever you're doing [laughter]
and you know in his answer was prepared
mind that he'd been thinking about IU
model sequential data ever since his PhD
in Canada. And when he saw the solution,
this was what he'd been waiting for for
like a decade. And so he could jump on
it. And then when you start thinking
about prepared mind, you know, you would
probably remember this better than I do,
but wasn't there a um Seattle Seahawks
Super Bowl final against the New England
Patriots where the New England
quarterback like does an interception in
the last second of play and clinches the
victory. And when he's asked after the
play, how did you know to make that run?
Where did you how did you know where the
quarterback was going to throw the ball?
The answer was prepared mind. basically
he didn't use that phrase but you know
in training they had studied
the play that the Seattle Seahawks were
going to make and they knew that given a
certain formation when the ball was
snapped back there was a certain pass
that was coming so the guy just takes
off and he runs right into where the
ball comes and he catches it and
intercepts and New England wins and so
that's a prepared mind in sports
>> and the other reason last thing
>> I would put on the billboard prepare
your mind is that for the age of
artificial intelligence. This is what we
need to hear. And this is a serious
point, right? The risk with large
language models is that we just get lazy
and whenever we need to know something,
we just get it to tell us what to think.
That is not the route to happiness or
satisfaction or anything. We need to
continue to do the hard work of
preparing our minds because that's what
makes us people. You know, I think,
therefore I am. And so I think prepare
your mind is entering a time when it
becomes a more important slogan than
ever.
>> How do you do that for yourself? What
guard rails or policies have you
established for your own use of AI?
>> And it makes me also think of going to
the gym, lifting weights, getting in
cardio. You don't have to do that, but
it is beneficial for you on a lot of
levels. And people, some people find it
quite enjoyable, right? And hence they
do that. And I'm wondering
what the equivalent is for knowledge
workers or people who are preparing
their minds and
don't want to become sort of impotent in
the way that people with directions have
mostly become impotent because of Google
maps and other tools like that. Right?
So what do you what do you do for
yourself personally or how are you
thinking about that? The first thing I
think is that the Google Maps analogy is
the wrong one in the sense that it's
fine to offload a very specific mental
task which to most people is a pain in
the neck.
>> Mhm.
>> And let the machine do that for you.
It's not fine to offload all thinking,
[laughter] right? The point of
offloading something should be you get
to focus your mental energy more on the
other stuff that you really get
satisfaction and meaning from. And so
for me, what that means is that I'm very
happy to use large language models to
learn about the scientific output of
somebody I'm going to interview next
week.
>> Mhm. All of these AI papers are on
archive and the model has ingested all
of them and the model is extremely good
at telling me okay the scientist you're
seeing next week has these three papers
and the progression between the three
papers is this and this and this and the
comparison with the person you saw two
weeks ago is this and this and this and
you know you learn a lot from the system
like really bootstraps you to learn
faster so that's helping me to think
more not to think less.
>> It's cutting out the time it would take
me to go find all the papers by myself
and then labor through them. It's
cutting to the chase and nourishing me
intellectually.
>> And by the way, I'm not worried about
hallucination because I'm going to
interview the human scientist anyway.
So, I get to cross-check it all.
>> What I would never do is get the AI to
write because frankly, it's not very
good at long form. In fact, it really
sucks. It's fine for writing an email,
although I don't do that either because
I like writing. But it really is. I've
tried it once. It's terrible for
anything longer than about 800 words.
But even if it could do it, I don't
think I would ever outsource that
because that's me,
>> right? This is what I do. This is the
thinking process. I think through my
writing, I come to understand what I
understand and think what I think and
believe what I believe through writing.
And I'm not going to give that up.
>> I'm letting out a pensive exhale because
I was thinking of this. A friend said to
me, well, I'll give him credit. Kevin
Rose, at one point I was I wouldn't say
complaining, observing that AI couldn't
do X or it wasn't very good at Y.
>> He said, when was the last time you
tried that? I was like six months ago.
And he's like, try it again. And
[laughter] so the rules will become
really important as also the power of
these things increases. And there I want
to say it was the New Yorker. There was
a piece in the New York or it might have
been the New York Times with some very
famous I want to say novelist could have
been Pulitzer Prize winner in literature
somebody at the top and they took three
or four pieces of their own writing had
AI generate three or four pieces of
writing in their voice and gave it to
professional readers
editors and so on and it wasn't clear
people couldn't figure out they claimed
that what he or she wrote was AI.
>> How long was the piece of writing? I
knew that was the question you're gonna
ask and I and I don't recall. So I want
to go back and look at that piece to
see.
>> So there was a story precisely like that
from an economist writer who's very
funny and also does podcasts
>> and he ran that experiment and it was
just as you said, you know, his friends
who were professional economist
journalists couldn't tell which was the
witty column that he'd written versus
the equally witty ones [laughter] which
the Lamb had generated. And he was very
pissed off with this. And I look, I take
your point. I mean, for now, I can be
all complacent and say, "Yeah, it only
works for 800 words. It doesn't work for
a whole chapter, which is 20 pages
long." But no doubt it'll get better and
better. But I still think I'm going to
cling on to the thing that makes me me.
>> For sure, 100%. And I think doing the
thinking, preparing your mind
in part, asking that question, which is
not an easy question, perhaps there's a
different way to phrase it, but like
what what are the things that make me
me? So you don't accidentally make
sacrifices that start to erode your
sense of self, [snorts] but also sense
of selfworth.